SAM ANDERSON

andersonsamalex@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/sam-alex-anderson

Personal Statement

I am a recent first class aerospace engineering graduate specialising in space technology and rocketry; with a keen interest in the wider application of aerospace technology.

Having had a variety of roles both in and out of university has allowed me to become a fast learner who can quickly adapt to new roles and responsibilities.

Key Skills

Problem Solving: Highly developed problem solving skills honed at university, my hobby of

programming and out in the field during my role as a concrete cutter.

Teamwork: Strong team player demonstrated through university group projects, sailing

experience and various other team sports such as rugby, football and American

football.

Software Skills: Microsoft Office, Catia V5, MATLAB, C#, Visual Basic, ANSYS, HTML, CSS,

Javascript, PHP, Python and React.js.

Education

2015-2019 Bachelor Degree at the University of Hertfordshire.

- First Class Honours BEng Aerospace Engineering with Space Technology and Study Abroad Year.
- Thesis: 'Conceptual design of an asteroid sample return spacecraft.' (awarded the Blue Streak prize).

2017 Sem 1 Exchange Semester at the Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya.

• MEng Space and Aeronautical Engineering in Barcelona, Spain.

2017 Sem 2 Exchange Semester at the Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology.

• BEng Aerospace Engineering in Melbourne, Australia.

Employment History

April 2020-Current Mask Manufacturer at Taylor Martin Recruitment Ltd.

- Role involves assembling visor masks for use in NHS hospitals and care homes to combat Covid-19.
- Skills developed include working to a strict quota, helping to establish a working production line.

Summers of 2015-2019 Concrete Cutter at SA Concrete Cutting Ltd.

- Responsibilities include maintaining, transporting and use of equipment. Working safely in a hazardous environment.
- The skills developed include interpersonal connections between coworkers, employers and peers; problem solving skills gained through troubleshooting issues in the field; the application and abidance to safe working practises.

Aug 2019-Sept 2019 Personal Shopper at Ocado Ltd.

- This role involved working in -25°C conditions inside a freezer while maintaining a strict work rate.
- Skills developed include adherence to strict quotas and deadlines; workplace perseverance under pressure and diligence.

Voluntary Work

2015-Present

Watch Leader at the Rona Sailing Project.

- Voyages taking young and disadvantaged people out to sea; in order to teach them life skills such as cooking, cleaning and teamwork.
- Leadership, teamwork and mentoring experience.

Sept 2013-May 2015 Teaching Assistant at the Brunts Academy.

• Aiding the learning of students aged 11-16 in the science curriculum.

Other Courses

- Applied machine learning.
- · Web technologies.

Awards and Achievements

- Blue Streak Prize awarded by the Royal Aeronautical Society for the best final year specialist rocketry project by an aerospace engineering student.
- Competed in the 2015 Tall Ships Race and the 2017 Tall Ships Regatta.
- RYA Competent Crew award.
- CSCS labourer qualification.
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold award.
- Full Clean UK Drivers License.

References

Available upon request.